Sillitoe mss. II, 1950-1996 LMC 2141
Lilly Library
- II. Writings (Box 2)
  - MAJOR WORKS (Box 2)
    - Out of the Whirlpool (Box 14)
      - folder 6: First draft, autograph and typescript, ca. 210 pages (Box 14)
      - folder 7: Second draft, revised typescript, 152 pages (Box 14)
      - folder 8: Third draft, revised typescript, 123 pages (Box 14)
      - folder 9: Final typescript, no revisions (Box 14)
    - The Palisade (Box 14)
      - folder 10: Revised typescript of an unpublished novel, lacking Chapter 1 (used in The Open Door), 26 autograph pages, 305 typescript pages. This book was written at Soller in, 1957 (Box 14)
    - The Ragman's Daughter (Box 14)
      - folder 11: Typescript of introduction; paperback cover (Box 14)
      - folder 12: The Bike - four unrevised typescripts, 29 pages; revised typescript, 7 pages (Box 14)
      - folders 13-14: The Firebug - second draft, revised typescript, with 8 pages of autograph manuscript, 23 pages; third draft, typescript, no revisions, 25 pages; fourth draft, revised typescript, 24 pages; penultimate draft, revised typescript, 23 pages; final draft, revised typescript, 25 pages; draft, revised typescript, with one page of autograph manuscript, 24 pages; unrevised typescript for the printer of pp. 48-73 of the book (Box 14)
      - folder 15-17: The Good Woman - first draft, autograph manuscript40 pages; second draft, revised typescript, 36 pages; draft, revised typescript, 33 pages; three unrevised typescript drafts; incomplete typescript drafts with a few revisions; unrevised typescript for the printer of pp. 171-225 of the book, Jan. 22, 1962; 1961 (Box 14)
      - folders 18-20: The Magic Box - autograph, revised manuscript entitled the Black Box 37 pages; first draft, revised typescript, pages; revised typescript; unrevised typescript; unrevised typescript for the printer of pp. 74-118 of the book; printed galley for London Magazine, Dec. 26, 1961; Dec. 30, 1961 (Box 14)
      - folder 21: The Other John Pell - second draft, revised typescript, 9 pages; third draft, corrected typescript, 7 pages; four typescripts, no revisions (Box 14)
      - folders 22-24: The Ragman's Daughter - autograph, 1st draft21 pages; revised typescript, 26 pages; three revised typescripts; five unrevised typescripts; typescript with revisions and printer's marks, 37 pages, Feb. 20, 1962; Mar. 8, 1962 (Box 14)
      - folders 1: The Ragman's Daughter - autograph,... (Box 15)
      - folders 2-3: To be Collected - first draft, incomplete, mostly autograph, 19 pages; second draft, revised typescript, with one page of autograph manuscript on the verso of The Rats 29 pages; third draft, revised typescript, 42 pages; unrevised typescript copy for the printer of pp. 130-170; miscellaneous pages (Box 15)
    - Raw Material (Box 1)
      - folder 4: Notebook and loose autograph pages (Box 1)
      - folder 5: Second draft, revised typescript, ca. 120 pages (Box 1)
      - folders 6-7: Third draft, revised typescript, ca. 200 pages (Box 1)
      - folders 8-9: Fourth draft, revised typescript, ca. 200 pages (Box 1)
      - folders 10-11: Fifth draft, revised typescript, 261 pages (Box 1)
      - folders 12-13: Sixth draft, revised typescript, 264 pages (Box 1)
      - folder 14: Miscellaneous autograph and typescript pages (Box 1)
      - folders 15-16: Printer's copy, ca. 350 pages (Box 1)
    - Road to Volgagrad (Box 15)
      - folder 17: Notebook and loose autograph pages (Box 15)
      - folders 18-19: Two revised typescript drafts (Box 15)
      - folder 20: Printer's copy (Box 15)
      - folder 1: Printer's copy (Box 16)
    - Saturday Night and Sunday Morning (Box 16)
      - folder 2: Canning Circus autograph manuscript with two typed pages which became Saturday Night and Sunday Morning, 10 pages., Feb. 22, 1953 (Box 16)
        On versos of pages 3-10 of a story called Spider's Trap (only pages extant) and two pages of Mr. Sing, a very early story set in Malaya.
      - folder 3: Autograph notes on novels made while writing Saturday Night and Sunday Morning, one typescript page on verso of Mr. Allen's Island; two autograph notes; paperback covers; transparency for cover art; photocopies of two illustrations (Box 16)
    - The Second Chance and Other Stories (Box 16)
      - folders 4-18: Autograph and typescript drafts of the following short stories: Confrontation; The Devil's Almanack; Ear to the Ground; The Fiddle; The Gate of a Great Mansion; The Meeting; No Name on the Street; A Scream of Toys; The Second Chance; The Sniper; A Time to Keep (Box 16)
      - folders 19-20: Draft of book, typescript (Box 16)
      - folders 21-22: Printer's copy (Box 16)
    - Snowstop (Box 16)
      - folders 23-25: Three notebooks, autograph, ca.300 pages, with inserted notes and an introduction to an atlas of trench maps by Peter Chasseaud (Box 16)
      - folders 1-2: Second draft, revised typescript, 435 pages (Box 17)
      - folders 3-5: Third draft, revised typescript, ca. 500 pages (Box 17)
      - folders 6-10: Fourth draft, two copies, revised typescripts, Oct. 22, 1991 (Box 17)
      - folders 11-13: Printer's copy (Box 17)
      - folder 14: Uncorrected proof, including book jacket proof (Box 17)
    - A Start in Life (Box 17)
      - folders 15-17: Autograph manuscript, 474 pages, and cards and notes (Box 17)
      - folders 1-3: Second draft, revised typescript, 628 pages (Box 18)
      - folder 4-8: Final draft, revised typescript and photocopy, ca. 600 pages each (Box 18)
    - A Stay of Some Time (Box 18)
      - folder 9: Revised typescript of an unpublished travel book, the title of which was taken from theedition of Baedeker's Spain and Portugal., 1913 (Box 18)
        Lacks Chapter 1 (the scenic notes from which were used in Death of William Posters), 248 pages.
    - The Storyteller (Box 18)
      - folders 10-14: Miscellaneous autograph and typescript pages (Box 18)
      - folders 1-3: Ante penultimate draft revised typescript, 407 pages (Box 19)
      - folders 4-6: Final draft, revised typescript, 431 pages (Box 19)
    - Three Plays (Box 19)
      - folders 7-16: Autograph and typescript drafts for the following plays: The Interview; Pit Strike; and The Slot Machine (formerly: This Foreign Field), with photograph of Sillitoe beginning to write it onin Shropshire, Sept. 28, 1964 (Box 19)
      - folder 17: Preface, four revised autograph and typescript copies; invitation to first performance (Box 19)
      - folder 18-19: Printer's copy (Box 19)
    - Travels in Nihilon (Box 19)
      - folder 20: Notes, loose and notebook (Box 19)
      - folders 21: Autograph manuscript, loose and notebook, 262 pages (Box 19)
      - folders 1: Autograph manuscript,... (Box 20)
      - folders 2-3: Second draft, revised typescript, 300 pages (Box 20)
      - folders 4-5: Third draft, revised typescript, 323 pages (Box 20)
      - folder 6: Final draft(?), pp. 402-410 only (Box 20)
    - Autograph first draft, 181 pages, folio volume (16 x 12 inches), Apr. 8, 1965-Jan. 15, 1967 (Oversize 1)
      - folders 7-9: Second draft, revised typescript, finished in one of Grave's houses, revisions finished436 pages, Apr. 17, 1967 (Box 20)
      - folders 10-11: Final draft, revised typescript, 406 pages (Box 20)
      - folder 12: Chapter XIV, galley (Box 20)
      - folder 13: Map of the Soller/Deya area with passages of the novel on it, 1965-1966 (Box 20)
    - The Widower's Son (Box 20)
      - folders 14-16: Second draft, autograph (Box 20)
      - folders 17-18: Third draft, revised typescript (Box 20)
      - folder 19: Fourth draft, revised typescript (Box 20)
      - folder 1-2: Fourth draft,... (Box 21)
      - folders 3-4: Draft, revised typescript (Box 21)
      - folders 5-7: Miscellaneous draft pages, revised typescript (Box 21)
      - folders 8-10: Printer's copy (Box 21)
  - ARTICLES AND SHORT STORIES (Box 21)
    Autograph and typed revised drafts of articles, introductions, scripts, speeches, reviews, contributions to books and newspapers including the following titles:
    - Abstract and Modern (Box 21)
    - Against Ideology (Box 21)
    - The Air Conditioned Sauna (Box 21)
    - The Artist and His Relationship with Society (Box 21)
    - The Baikal Hound (Box 21)
    - Bennett's Letters (Box 21)
    - Bernard Sindall (Box 21)
    - Biking in France (Box 21)
    - The Book I Never Wrote (Box 21)
    - The Burren (Box 21)
    - Catalina, (unpublished) (Box 21)
    - A Century of Baedeker (Box 21)
    - Chance Reading (Box 21)
    - Chauvinistic (Box 21)
    - Comments on the Struga Festival (Box 21)
    - The Confidence Trick (Box 21)
    - Contemporary Proletarian Novelists (Box 21)
    - Dear Six Writers (Box 21)
    - Derbyshire (Box 21)
    - Diary for Guardian (Box 21)
    - Distance (Box 21)
    - Dobris (Box 21)
    - The Ebro, Not Wigan Pier (Box 21)
    - Education (Box 21)
    - Egypt (Box 21)
    - Eight Golden Sovereigns (Box 21)
    - First Day in Israel (Box 21)
    - The Flight of Arrows (Box 21)
    - The Freedom Games (Box 21)
    - The Freedom of the Individual in Society (Box 21)
    - Gift of Stones (Box 21)
    - Good Books (Box 21)
    - Happy Families (Box 21)
    - Have Soul, Will Travel (Box 21)
    - Helen Marshall (Box 21)
    - Israel and Lebanon (Box 21)
    - Jack London (Box 21)
    - Japan Journal (Box 21)
    - The Last Romantic (Box 21)
    - London (Box 21)
    - The Long Distance Runner Today (Box 21)
    - Lowestoft (Box 21)
    - Luxury at Luxor (Box 21)
    - Macbett, [review of the Ionesco play] (Box 22)
    - Malayan Jungle (Box 22)
    - Mons-Ham Walk (Box 22)
    - Mother and Son (Box 22)
    - My Country Childhood (Box 22)
    - My Favourite Magazine (Box 22)
    - My First Job (Box 22)
    - My First Novel (Box 22)
    - My Moment of Success (Box 22)
    - My Opinion of Opinions (Box 22)
    - 1940s, 1950s (Box 22)
    - Notes on the Painting of Phillip Martin (Box 22)
    - On Che Guevara (Box 22)
    - On the Tribulations of Translating (Box 22)
    - One Germany - Almost (Box 22)
    - Orwell (Box 22)
    - Patterson, Friend of Zion (Box 22)
    - Peterborough (Box 22)
    - A Plain Man's Guide to the Soul (Box 22)
    - Plays or Novels (Box 22)
    - The Poachers (Box 22)
    - Politics (Box 22)
    - Raleigh (Box 22)
    - Reflections on Zurich (Box 22)
    - Responsibility (Box 22)
    - Robbed! (Box 22)
    - Robert Graves (Box 22)
    - Robert Graves: King Jesus (Box 22)
    - Saint Pargoire and the Revolution (Box 22)
    - The Scarlet Town (Box 22)
    - The Second Birth of Children (Box 22)
    - Sergeant Mud (Jones) (Box 22)
    - Shorts and Long Shorts (Box 22)
    - Spycatcher (Box 22)
    - Support for Israel (Box 22)
    - To Wake Up Living (Box 22)
    - Travel and Art (Box 22)
    - Tribulations Seen in the Picture of a Great Lord (Box 22)
    - Under Spiritual Horizons (Box 22)
    - Underground is Where it Happens (Box 22)
    - A Visit to Lod Youth Day Centre and Neve Village (Box 22)
    - A way for Writers in the Admass Age (Box 22)
    - What Comes on Monday? (Box 22)
    - Wolstonecraft (Box 22)
    - Work (Box 22)
    - Untitled articles and fragments, including one folder of autobiographical writings, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - BOOK REVIEWS, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    Arranged alphabetically by author and book reviewed:
    - Baroja, Pio. The Troubled World (Box 22)
    - Callow, Phillip. Native Ground (Box 22)
    - Carras, Jacques. Beyond the Tunnel of History (Box 22)
    - Dixon, Norman F. On the Psychology of National Incompetence (Box 22)
    - Durrell, Lawrence. Collected Poems (Box 22)
    - Fink, Ida. Scrap of Time and Other Stories [?] (Box 22)
    - Flender, Harold. Rescue in Denmark and Warmbrunn, Werner. The Dutch Under German Occupation, 1940-1945 (Box 22)
    - Frank, Anne. Tales from the Secret Annexe, translated by Talph Manheim and Michel Mok (Box 22)
    - Galey, John. Sinai and the Monastery of St. Catherine (Box 22)
    - Gericault. A Horse Frightened by Lightning (Box 22)
    - Gosling, Ray. Personal Copy (Box 22)
    - Greave, Peter. The Painted Leopard (Box 22)
    - Harris, Frank. Bomb (Box 22)
    - Hassel, Sven. The Wheels of Terror and Sentjurc, Igor. Prayer for an Assassin and Braun, Andrei. The Paving Stones of Hell (Box 22)
    - Hattersley, Roy. The Maker's Mark (Box 22)
    - Hilton, Enid. More Than One Life (Box 22)
    - Jones, Glyn. The Learning Lark (Box 22)
    - King, Robin. The Angry Sun (Box 22)
    - Kolar, Jean. Return Fare (Box 22)
    - Lanzmann, Jacques. The American Rat (Box 22)
    - Lassell, Margaret. Wellington Road (Box 22)
    - Lawrence, D.H. Fantasia of the Unconscious and Psychoanalysis and the Unconscious (Box 22)
    - Mitford, Nancy. Don't Tell Alfred (Box 22)
    - Morton, H.V. In Search of the Holy Land (Box 22)
    - Nixon, Edna. Voltaire and the Calas Case (Box 22)
    - Norman, Frank. Stand on Me (Box 22)
    - Plomer, William. Collected Poems (Box 22)
    - Priestley, J.B. Literature and Western Man and Hadgraft, Cecil. Australian Literature (Box 22)
    - Pudney, John. Home and Away: An Autobiographical Gambit (Box 22)
    - Sagan, Francoise. Aimez-vous Brahms and Connell, Evan S. Mrs. Bridge and Durrell, Lawrence. Clea and Walser, Martin. The Gadarene Club (Box 22)
    - Salivarova, Zdena. Summer in Prague (Box 22)
    - Saroyan, William. The Human Comedy (Box 22)
    - Shah, Idris. Wisdom of the Idiots (Box 22)
    - Shadbolt, Maurice. The New Zealanders (Box 22)
    - Sher, Anthony. Middlepost (Box 22)
    - Sigal, Clancy. Weekend in Dinlock (Box 22)
    - Singer, I.J. The Brothers Ashkenazi (Box 22)
    - Storey, David. This Sporting Life (Box 22)
    - Trease, Geoffrey. Nottingham: A Biography (Box 22)
    - Trevor, William. A Writer's Ireland (Box 22)
    - Updike, John. A Month of Sundays (Box 22)
    - van der Post, Laurence. Journey Into Russia (Box 22)
    - Voynich, E.L. The Gadfly (Box 22)
    - Waugh, Evelyn. A Tourist in Africa (Box 22)
    - Wyndham, John. Trouble With Lichen (Box 22)
  - INTRODUCTIONS, (17 folders) (Box 22)
    Introductions written by Sillitoe for the following books:
    - Allen, Walter. All in a Lifetime (Box 22)
    - Bryson, Emrys. Portrait of Nottingham (Box 22)
    - Chasseaud, Peter. Topological Atlas of, 1914-18 (Box 22)
    - Dor, Moshe. The Burning Bush (Box 22)
    - Green, G.F. Land Without Heroes (Box 22)
    - Hamilton, Alex. As If She Were Mine (Box 22)
    - Longman Education., [group of stories by Sillitoe used in untitled collection] (Box 22)
    - McGrath, Pat. The Green Leaves of Nottingham (Box 22)
    - Perret, Christopher. Memory of a Parasite (Box 22)
    - Sawkins, John. Poetry (Box 22)
    - Toft, John. The Wedge (Box 22)
    - White, Gilbert. The Journals of Gilbert White (Box 22)
    - Unidentified authors and books, (5 folders) (Box 22)
  - POETRY (Box 22)
    Many of these poems also appear in the published collections of poetry section.
    Individual poems. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    Contains autograph and typescript drafts and final copies.
    Poem list:
    Abundance
    Age
    Albertina or The Fly-sting or The Daily Venomous Needle of the Gnat
    Alchemist
    Aleph
    Alioth
    Altamira
    Ark
    Artist's Studio
    Atomic Goodnight
    Autumn
    Autumn 1971
    Baby
    Barbarians
    Be Your Age
    The Blacksmith's Song
    Bouquet
    Cabo Finisterre
    Cancer
    Car Dump
    Car Fights Cat
    Cat Camouflage
    Caves
    Chain
    Changing Course
    Chasing the Dead
    Choppers
    Coast Near Nahariya
    Concerto
    Convalescence
    Creation
    A Crying Child
    Day-Dream Communique
    The Dead
    Dead Fly
    Dead Man's Grave
    Dead Sea Talk
    The Death of a Bird
    Death of Ehrenberg
    The Demon Lover
    Departure
    Dialogue
    Ditchling Beacon
    Dividers
    Duel Navigation
    Eagledream
    The early morning departure of the Car Nicobar Special from Butterworth, Malaya
    Early School
    Ein Gedi
    Empty Quarter
    End
    Epitaph
    Esther
    Eurasia: Jetnotes
    Eve
    Exfiltration
    Ezekiel
    The Fall
    Farewell
    Fascist Youth Rally outside Malaga Cathedral
    Fate of an icicle
    February Poems
    Festival
    A Few Lines on Malvern Abbey
    Fifth Avenue
    Finland
    Fire
    First Poem
    The Fish of the Zodiacs
    Fishes
    Follow the Deepsea Fish
    For a Jewish Prisoner in Russia
    For Ruth
    Fox
    Francoise
    Frog Poem
    Full-Bawd
    Full Moon Through a Telescope
    Full Moon's Tongue
    Gambler
    Geographers in Love
    Ghosts
    Goddess
    Goodbye Kursk
    Gulf of Bothnia
    Guide to the Tiflis Highway
    The Hanged Man
    Hephzibah
    Honour
    Horse on Wenlock Edge
    Hospital Sunset
    House
    Housewife
    How to Keep Thin in a Fat Society
    Hunger
    I Love You
    I tell myself...
    Illness
    In Israel, Driving to the Dead Sea
    In Summer and South...
    Intruder
    Irkutsk 1963
    Israel
    Kettle
    Killing
    Kindergarten
    The Knight in the Tiger's Skin
    Lady of Bapaume
    Lake District Cottage
    Lamp Post
    Last Thoughts
    Learning Hebrew
    Left as a Desert
    Left Handed
    Lenz
    The Life-Flame
    Lightning
    Lizard
    Long Love, Lost Love
    Louise
    Love in the Environs of Voronezh
    Love is a Broken Heart
    Lovers
    Lover's Plea
    Love's Mansion
    Lucifer's Bridge
    Made For Each Other
    Man and Woman
    The Map
    March Birth
    Mayday-Mayday-Mayday
    Meeting (2)
    Mercutio's Pintable Death
    Mixed Up Mystic Thoughts Of A Midwestern Missile Man
    The Moon
    Morning
    Moth
    Nails
    Naked
    A New Rich
    Newspapers
    Night
    North Star Rocket
    Nottingham Castle
    Nuclear Warning
    O Why grow You Afraid...
    Odours
    An Old Friend Reaching Jerusalem
    Old Man
    On First Going Into a Factory to Work
    On First taking Streptomycin
    On Seeing Jerusalem
    On the Last Soldier Killed in the War of Independence for Israel, 1948-9
    The One and Only Love
    The One Too Many
    Open Plan
    Optics
    Oxney
    Pander
    Peace-time Guns
    Picnic
    Piddinghoe Elegy
    Pieces of Eight
    Pilgrim
    Pilgrims' Route
    Place Without a Name
    Plague Meeting
    Poem (2)
    Poem Left by a Dead Man
    Poem Written on the Hereford Train
    The Poet
    Poetry
    Poet's Chauffeur
    Rabbit
    Railway Station
    Rats
    Real
    Rebels
    The Reckoning
    Reflections on July 1
    Resurrection
    Ride It Out
    The Rights of Man
    The River
    The River Has Burst Its Banks
    The Rock
    Romeo
    Rose
    Ruth
    St. Pancras
    Salt Poem
    Samenessess
    Say Sheffield
    The Sea of Galilee
    Sea Talk
    Secret Sources
    Semipalatinsk
    Shaman
    The Shropshire Woman
    Siberian Lake
    Signal Box
    Silence and Stillness
    Sleep
    Smile
    Snow at Aix
    Snow on the North Side of Lucifer
    Soldiers' Ditty
    Somme
    Song
    Sonja's Dead Horse
    Spanish New Year
    The Spider and the Fly
    Stars
    Stones in Picardy
    Storm
    Storm (at Bellagio)
    Strategy
    Suicide
    Surveying
    Survival
    Synagogue in Prague - 1963
    Terrorist
    Thirteen Lines
    This New Dimension
    Thistles
    Those Stupid Little Trumpets of the Lord
    Thoughts in Hospital
    Through the Jungle
    To Esther
    To the New Moon
    Toasting
    Toni Moreno
    The Track
    Tramp on the Coast of Life
    The Traveller
    Travelling
    Tree
    Twentieth Century Elegy
    Two Cities
    Two on Easter Sunday
    Unity
    Unlucky Poem
    View from Misk Hill
    Vision
    W
    Waking
    Warning
    We
    The Weight of Summer
    What is Love?
    The White Path
    Who Died of Love
    Wild Cat
    Window
    Wood-in-Oxney
    Woods
    Xmas
    A Year Carol
    Yes
    - A-C (Box 22)
    - D-Z (Box 22)
      - Group of poems sent to Madge Hale (?) to critique (Box 22)
      - Portuguese translations of poems by Sillitoe (Box 22)
      - Russian translations of poems by Sillitoe (Box 22)
      - untitled poems (Box 22)
      - Alan Sillitoe: Collected Poems, (1 folder) (Box 23)
      - A Falling Out of Love, (2 folders) (Box 23)
      - Love in the Environs of Voronezh, (3 folders) (Box 23)
      - Poems for Shakespeare, by Sillitoe, et al., (1 folder) (Box 23)
      - The Rats and Other Poems, (1 folder) (Box 23)
      - Snow on the North Side of Lucifer, (3 folders) (Box 23)
      - Snow on the North Side (cont.), (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - Storm and Other Poems (Box 24)
      - Sun Before Departure, (4 folders) (Box 24)
      - Tides and Stone Walls, (5 folders) (Box 24)
  - SCRIPTS (Box 24)
    - Che. Autograph and corrected typescripts of film script, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - The Fishing Boat Picture. Corrected typescript of an early draft of film script, headed Uncle Harry 6 pages (Box 24)
      (not complete)
    - Fuente Ovejuna, by Lope de Vega. Autograph, corrected typescripts and mimeographs. Translated and adapted by Sillitoe and Ruth Fainlight, and titled Citizens as Soldiers., (5 folders) (Box 24)
    - Hail to the Globoes! A one act play. Carbon typescript (Box 24)
    - The Loneliness of the Long-distance Runner (Box 24)
    - Typescript of a play, adapted by Stephen Jameson and Paul Brennen (Box 24)
    - Corrected typescript of a film-script, 162 pages (Box 24)
    - Carbon typescript and photocopy of a multi-media stage play, by Harry L. Murray. Including contents, stage directions and drawings, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - On Saturday Afternoon. Mimeograph of broadcast script of a short story from The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner. Third Programme, Transmission:, 16 Nov. 1959 (Box 25)
    - Pit Strike. Typescript and carbon of television script. (Box 25)
    - The Ragman's Daughter. Film script. First draft, autograph and typescript copies; second draft, revised typescript, including excised passages, four pages of loose autograph notes; third draft, revised typescript; draft, mimeographwith undated letter from Harold Becker; Harold Becker's notes on the script; notes by Sillitoe; autograph plan for the film script, Apr. 26, 1970; (5 folders) (Box 25)
    - Saturday Night and Sunday Morning. Incomplete autograph and typescript film script. The first page has suggestions by Karel Reisz. Includes program for showing at the Mediatheque Gutenberg and a showbill for The Baronet Theatre, New York City, 1990 (Box 25)
    - Saturday Night and Sunday Morning. Typescript of play script, some pages revised in another hand (probably made at the suggestion of Frank Dunlop) at the Prince of Wales Theatre in, 1965 (Box 25)
    - A Start in Life. Autograph and typescript of synopsis for film (Box 25)
  - SPEECHES (Box 25)
    - 1959-1989, (8 folders) (Box 25)
      Arranged chronologically by date given. Followed by several interviews.
  - TRANSLATIONS (Box 25)
    - Botev, Khristo. Translations of various poems from Bulgarian (Box 25)
    - Martin, Collete. Journey to Morocco. (Box 25)
      Including Sillitoe's translation of Martin's article A Woman in the Desert. The article was published in The Geographical Magazine, without Sillitoe recognized as the translator
  - FRAGMENTS (Box 25)
    - Unfinished or fragments of articles and other writings, (1 folder) (Box 25)
  - WRITINGS BY OTHERS (Box 25)
    - Articles, broadcasts and other writings about Sillitoe. Other writings such as poetry not related to Sillitoe., (2 folders) (Box 25)
- III. Miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - FINANCIAL MATERIALS, (4 folders) (Box 25)
    Includes bank receipts, tax papers, royalty statements, correspondence with accountants, financial statements
  - MISCELLANY, (6 folders) (Box 25)
    Contains flyers announcing speaking engagements for Sillitoe and brochures for festivals, symposia, etc. where Sillitoe was a participant
  - CLIPPINGS (Box 25-27)